Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- United States Attorney for Western Pennsylvania, 1969-1975; VII.
  - News Releases, 2.
    - January-June, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Thornburgh announced the appointment of four additional Assistant U.S. Attorneys, April 12, 1971; 15.
      - Letter sent from Thornburgh to the Chiefs of the Probation Office of twenty-five PA counties, April, 1971; 16.
      - 26 defendants, named in two indictments returned last month on charges of violating the federal gambling laws, entered pleas of not guilty, April 27, 1971; 17.
      - A federal court jury convicted Robert Howard Brown of assault on a federal officer with a deadly weapon, April 29, 1971; 18.
      - Thornburgh will be the principal speaker at a Law Day dinner sponsored by the McKean County Bar Association, April 30, 1971; 19.
      - Judge Edward Dumbauld fined a contractor and the two construction companies he owns and operates a total of $15,000 for failure to pay workmen time and 1/2 for overtime, May 3, 1971; 20.
      - Clarence Scott was sentenced to five years in prison for devising a credit card scheme to defraud major oil companies and the Mellon National Bank, May 3, 1971; 21.
      - A federal court jury convicted Harry Croft McKelvey on nine counts of misapplication of funds of two local banking institutions, May 4, 1971; 22.
      - A federal court jury found Donald R. Brenneman guilty on four counts of violation the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, May 11, 1971; 23.
      - Thornburgh will address the Christy Park Works' Management Club of the United States Steel Corporation, May 13, 1971; 24.
      - The Department of Justice filed a civil suit under the 1899 Refuse Act against Wheeling-Pittsburgh Steel Corporation to halt waste pollution from three of its plants, May 17, 1971; 25.
      - Nicholas Pecoraro was indicted for perjury in connection with a probe of illegal gambling and official corruption in Westmoreland County, May 27, 1971; 26.
      - A federal judge dismissed a suit filed by former Pittsburgh City Magistrate Leonard Civill, June 9, 1971; 27.
      - Thornburgh will be among top federal prosecutors from throughout the U.S. at a three day conference in Washington, D.C., June 15, 1971; 28.
      - A federal grand jury returned a nine-count indictment against a former bank Assistant Vice President in connection with an alleged fund understatement, June 23, 1971; 29.
      - Thornburgh filed federal criminal charges against Melvin W. Humphreys, Vice-president of Teamsters Local 249 for violation of the Interstate Commerce Act, June 25, 1971; 30.
    - July-September, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - A three-year prison sentence was handed out to a Coraopolis chemist found guilty of illegally manufacturing dl-amphetamine sulfate, July 6, 1971; 1.
      - Harold Calig entered a guilty plea to eight counts of criminal income tax fraud, July 9, 1971; 2.
      - FBI agents arrested two area men on charges of violating the new federal anti-gambling statutes, July 12, 1971; 3.
      - Thornburgh instituted criminal proceedings under the Refuse Act against Ashland Oil, Inc. for discharging refuse from its manufacturing establishment, July 13, 1971; 4.
      - Augustine Ferrone will begin serving a three month jail term for charges of assaulting federal officers, July 19, 1971; 5.
      - A former Pittsburgh area bank executive was sentenced to two months imprisonment on nine counts of misapplying $29,000 from two local banks, July 20, 1971; 6.
      - Guidelines for citizens who seek to gather evidence of water pollution in violation of the 1899 Refuse Act were announced today, July 22, 1971; 7.
      - A special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering in Western PA will reconvene in Pittsburgh, July 25, 1971; 8.
      - Nearly 75 FBI agents carried out raids on sites involved in the illegal gambling operations of Anthony Grosso, July 26, 1971; 9.
      - Four Western PA men indicted by the special organized crime grand jury, entered pleas of not guilty, July 27, 1971; 10.
      - A federal grand jury returned the first indictment under the new federal statute dealing with the corruption of local law enforcement officials by syndicated gambling interests, July 28, 1971; 11.
      - Six men were indicted on charges of conspiracy and mail fraud by the Special Anti-Organized Crime grand jury, July 28, 1971; 12.
      - A special federal grand jury returned two indictments against Thomas Pecora, Business Manager of Laborers Local 1058, July 28, 1971; 13.
      - A federal Judge awarded a total of $5,000 to three citizens who had furnished stream pollution information to U.S. Attorney, Richard Thornburgh, July 30, 1971; 14.
      - At the Rotary Club of Pittsburgh, Thornburgh will present a progress report on the federal government's efforts against organized crime in Western PA, August, 1971; 15.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Pittsburgh Police officer Leonard Monti on six counts of receiving and transporting stolen U.S. postage stamps, August 10, 1971; 15.
      - A federal grand jury indicted three men for jury tampering, August 11, 1971; 16.
      - Thornburgh will present a progress report on the federal government's efforts against organized crime, August 18, 1971; 17.
      - Thornburgh established a separate Appellate Division in his office to handle the increasing number of appeals in criminal cases, August 23, 1971; 18.
      - Harold Calig was sentenced to one day in jail and fined on charges of criminal income tax fraud, August 24, 1971; 19.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering will reconvene in Pittsburgh, September 12, 1971; 20.
      - Trial of 69 remaining criminal water pollution charges against three Pittsburgh steel producers will be delayed, September, 1971; 21.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a former member of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert Duggan's "Racket Squad" on perjury charges, September 15, 1971; 22.
      - Federal prosecutors have won the right to use certain eyewitness testimony in the retrial of William E. Zeiler on bank robbery charges, September 16, 1971; 23.
      - Six men indicted on charges of conspiracy and mail fraud entered pleas of not guilty in federal district court, September 16, 1971; 24.
      - Trial of four members of Local 341 of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters will commence today before Judge Rabe F. Marsh, Jr., September 21, 1971; 25.
    - October-December, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Allegheny County's criminal justice system requires a massive overhaul, October 1, 1971; 1.
      - A former member of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert Duggan's "Racket Squad" pleaded not guilty to perjury charges, October 6, 1971; 2.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering will reconvene in Pittsburgh, October 17, 1971; 3.
      - Two of three men indicted in connection with a conspiracy to procure perjured testimony will be arraigned in federal district court tomorrow, October 18, 1971; 4.
      - A federal court jury returned guilty verdicts against Anthony DiNucci and Ralph Genareo for receiving and selling Cadillac automobiles stolen and transported in interstate commerce during 1969, October 20, 1971; 5.
      - Thomas Pecora, Business Manager of Laborers Local 1058, will be arraigned on charges from two indictments returned last summer, October 21, 1971; 6.
      - Thornburgh announced the appointment of James A. Villanova as an Assistant United States Attorney, October 26, 1971; 7.
      - Thornburgh will be the featured speaker at the Student-Guest Public Forum, the annual Fayette County Republican Committee Banquet, and the fall meeting of Navy Chapter 50 of the Reserve Officers Association, October 27, 1971; 8.
      - A federal court jury returned guilty verdicts against the Mayor and Chief of Police of Jeannette together with the individual in charge of illegal numbers operations in that city, October 28, 1971; 9.
      - Thornburgh asked the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit to issue a writ of mandamus, October 29, 1971; 10.
      - Judge Joseph F. Weis ordered the appointment of a receiver for real estate which is owned by the Iannellis, who were indicted for violation of the federal anti-gambling statutes, November 3, 1971; 11.
      - Thornburgh filed a petition with the U.S. District Court, on behalf of the Secretary of Labor, charging civil and criminal contempt against William Fiore, November 3, 1971; 12.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering will reconvene in Pittsburgh, November 14, 1971; 13.
      - A special federal grand jury returned an indictment growing out of a gangland-style bombing in Plum Borough last summer, November 17, 1971; 14.
      - Five Thornburgh staff members are engaged in an effort to close the communication gap between law enforcement officials and young black Pittsburghers, November 22, 1971; 15.
      - Statement on the action of the grand jury against large scale illegal gambling enterprises in Western PA, December 8, 1971; 16.
      - A federal grand jury indicted ten persons on charges of violating the anti-gambling provisions of the Organized Crime Control Act of 1970, December 8, 1971; 17.
      - Milton J. Carp has been named Attorney-in-Charge of the U.S. Department of Justice "Strike Force" in Pittsburgh, December 10, 1971; 18.
      - Thornburgh and Joseph Dino announced the arrest of three individuals and the seizure of 30 pounds of marihuana, December 15, 1971; 19.
      - Judge Gerald J. Weber denied motions of James Hockenberry to dismiss perjury indictments returned against him, December 23, 1971; 20.
      - Assistant U.S. Attorneys Thomas A. Daley and Samuel J. Orr, III received Special Achievement Awards for superior performance, December 28, 1971; 21.
    - January-March, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Three persons allegedly involved in local gambling activities were arrested today, January 7, 1972; 1.
      - Thornburgh will address the Public Affairs Forum of the Golden Triangle YMCA on "Some Straight Talk About Wiretapping and Organized Crime.", January, 1972; 2.
      - Thornburgh filed three criminal charges against Pittsburgh industries under the 1899 Refuse Act, January 10, 1972; 3.
      - A federal court jury convicted former Allegheny County Detective James D. Hockenberry on 3 counts of perjury, January 21, 1972; 4.
      - Thornburgh announced that his office is investigating the circumstances surrounding the failure of six witnesses to testify for the government against Hockenberry, January, 1972; 5.
      - Thornburgh departs for a three day conference in Ohio of top federal law enforcement officials, January 26, 1972; 6.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Jack Greenberg and Dr. Vincent Sundry on narcotics charges, January 26, 1972; 7.
      - A federal grand jury indicted five Pittsburgh men for the threat to blow up a United Airline jet unless they received $250,000, January 26, 1972; 8.
      - The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit denied a new trial to convicted Pittsburgh narcotics dealer Calvin Clark, February 2, 1972; 9.
      - Thirty federal law enforcement officials met with President Nixon at the White House to discuss trafficking in narcotics and dangerous drugs, February 8, 1972; 10.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Leonard Monti\, Albert Vensel and Henry Zottola on charges of conversion and sale, February, 1972; 11.
      - Thornburgh filed the first legal actions brought in Western PA under the Federal Economic Stabilization Act of 1970, February 15, 1972; 12.
      - Judge Joseph F. Weis entered an order upholding the government's right to use wiretap evidence, February 16, 1972; 13.
      - Judge John L. Miller entered an injunction against Beacon Climax Furniture and Appliance Company based on the Federal Economic Stabilization Act of 1970, February 29, 1972; 14.
      - A few Beaver County residents were served with subpoenas requiring their appearance before the special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering in Western PA, March, 1972; 15.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a former District Attorney on tax evasion charges, March 7, 1972; 16.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a member of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert W. Duggan's Detective Bureau on perjury charges, March 8, 1972; 17.
      - A federal grand jury returned indictments against 20 individuals alleged to be involved in the distribution of heroin and cocaine in the Greater Pittsburgh area, March 10, 1972; 18.
      - Thornburgh will address the Carnegie Rotary Club at a luncheon meeting in Heidelberg, PA, March 14, 1972; 19.
      - Joseph Anthony Bertone was indicted on the charge of giving false information to the First Federal Savings and Loan Association of Pittsburgh, March 28, 1972; 20.
      - Thornburgh will address a community assembly of Rotary Clubs on the subject of "Toward a Safer Community.", March 28, 1972; 21.
      - Forty persons alleged to be involved in the Anthony Michael Grosso numbers operation were indicted by federal grand jury, March 29, 1972; 22.
    - April-June, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - A federal grand jury returned a three-count indictment charging three men in connection with an international theft, April 4, 1972; 1.
      - A federal grand jury returned a 23-count indictment against nine individuals alleged to be involved in international heroin traffic, April 4, 1972; 2.
      - The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit denied the appeals of Louis Socrates Davis and Ronald Monroe Fields, April 4, 1972; 3.
      - Former Allegheny County Detective James D. Hockenberry was sentenced to a year in prison, April 5, 1972; 4.
      - Thornburgh called for legislation regulating the private possession and use of handguns in PA, April 5, 1972; 5.
      - Thornburgh announced that his office is investigating consumer complaints about alleged deceptive practices involving the sale of graves to veterans, April 8, 1972; 6.
      - Earl Rager and Patricia Orbin were indicted on charges of mail fraud and violations of the Gun Control Act of 1968, April 12, 1972; 7.
      - Arthur Frendzel was indicted on charges of using the mails to obtain money by false pretenses, April 12, 1972; 8.
      - A federal grand jury returned an indictment of a United Mine Workers district official in Kentucky on a conspiracy charge, April 12, 1972; 9.
      - Thornburgh announced that an additional special grand jury will be empanelled for the purpose of investigating organized crime and racketeering, April 20, 1972; 10.
      - Anthony Michael Grosso and six other defendants will be arraigned tomorrow on illegal gambling charges, April 27, 1972; 11.
      - A federal court jury convicted Robert Iannelli and seven co-defendants of conspiracy and violation of the Federal Organized Crime Control Act of 1970, April 28, 1972; 12.
      - Three persons were indicted on conspiracy and mail fraud charges, May 3, 1972; 13.
      - Thornburgh announced the filing of civil penalty enforcement suits against seven Western PA coal operators, May 8, 1972; 14.
      - The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit turned down an appeal filed by Michael Riehl, Arthur Rinaldi and James Chick, May, 1972; 15.
      - Thornburgh will meet with representatives of the Western PA Chiefs of Police Association to discuss police corruption, May 14, 1972; 16.
      - Police Chief Donald Crandall of North Versailles and two others will be arraigned tomorrow on charges of conspiracy and mail fraud, May 17, 1972; 17.
      - Two members of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert W. Duggan's Detective Bureau were indicted today, May 23, 1972; 18.
      - Thornburgh announced that a special federal grand jury will be empanelled next month to investigate drug trafficking, May 23, 1972; 19.
      - Thornburgh will be the principal speaker at a meeting of the Allegheny Boroughs Association, May 25, 1972; 20.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering indicted four Pittsburgh men in connection with the operation of a large scale illegal gambling operation, June 6, 1972; 21.
      - Anthony Acon and Captain Louis Ceccerelli were indicted on perjury charges, June 6, 1972; 22.
      - Two members of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert W. Duggan's Detective Bureau will be arraigned in Pittsburgh, June 12, 1972; 23.
      - Statement on the dangers of links between organized crime leaders and organized labor leaders, June 15, 1972; 24.
      - Nicholas Lomakin pleaded guilty to charges of income tax evasion, June 15, 1972; 25.
      - A federal district court jury convicted two Pittsburgh area labor officials for violation of the Federal Landrum-Griffin Act, June 15, 1972; 26.
      - Aliquippa Police Captain Louis A. Ceccerelli will be arraigned on charges of perjury, June 16, 1972; 27.
      - A federal grand jury returned two indictments charging unlawful diversion of federal anti-poverty funds, June 21, 1972; 28.
      - Thornburgh filed suit against Midpoint Cogent, Inc. charging violation of the rent regulations issued under the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970, June 21, 1972; 29.
      - Three McKeesport men convicted of illegal wiretapping will be sentenced in U.S. District Court, June 22, 1972; 30.
      - A federal grand jury returned indictments against six persons for violations of Federal Firearms laws, June 22, 1972; 31.
      - A federal grand jury returned a nine-count indictment against a former bank Assistant Vice President in connection with an alleged fund understatement, June 23, 1972; 32.
      - A federal appeals court has denied relief to former Pittsburgh Magistrate Leonard A. Civill, June, 1972; 33.
      - Stiff jail terms were imposed on eight defendants convicted of participation in the large scale illegal gambling operation of Robert Iannelli, June 26, 1972; 34.
      - Federal authorities arrested a Pittsburgh attorney on charges relating to a purported fix of a drug case in Federal Court, June 26, 1972; 35.
      - Four men indicted earlier this month in connection with the operation of an alleged large-scale illegal gambling operation will be arraigned, June 29, 1972; 36.
      - Thornburgh filed civil penalty enforcement suits against twelve more coal operators under the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969, June 29, 1972; 37.
      - The first federal grand jury ever specially empanelled to look into organized crime and racketeering completes its service next week, June 1972; 38.
    - July-September, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Statement on the Port Authority Transit ordering its employees to use a car wash operated by John LaRocca, July 6, 1972; 1.
      - Attorney John W. Campbell, Jr. was indicted on charges relating to a purported fix of a drug case in federal court, July 10, 1972; 2.
      - An Altoona man was indicted for making false statements to the special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering, July 10, 1972; 3.
      - Eight Western PA residents were indicted by the special federal grand jury investigating organized crime and racketeering, July 10, 1972; 4.
      - A federal appeals court in Philadelphia has upheld the first conviction ever obtained in Western PA under the 1968 Federal Anti-Loan Sharking Act, July, 1972; 5.
      - Thornburgh filed civil penalty enforcement suits against four coal operators under the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act passed in 1969, July 25, 1972; 6.
      - Seven of eight residents charged with participation in illegal gambling and public corruption in Beaver County were arraigned today, July 26, 1972; 7.
      - Beaver County Sheriff John W. Hineman\, Jr. will be arraigned in federal court on charges of conspiring with numbers racketeers, August 2, 1972; 8.
      - Attorney John W. Campbell, Jr. will be arraigned on charges relating to a purported fix of a drug case in federal court, August 4, 1972; 9.
      - Nicholas Lomakin will have to serve 30 days in jail and pay a fine for federal income tax evasion, August 9, 1972; 10.
      - Thornburgh hailed passage by the U.S. Senate of legislation tightening restrictions on the manufacture and sale of handguns, August 10, 1972; 11.
      - Ten employees in the Thornburgh office have received commendations from U.S. Attorney General Kleindienst for superior performance, August, 1972; 12.
      - Judge Edward Dumbauld imposed fines on Leon and Robert Coslov for corporate income tax evasion, August 30, 1972
      - Texas Rangers have apprehended a Pittsburgh man, who was a fugitive from federal charges of sending a radio bomb to a Springdale business establishment, September, 1972; 13.
      - Judge Joseph Weis, Jr. ordered convicted gambler William Fusaro to jail for violation of the terms of bail, September 6, 1972; 14.
      - Dr. William Catena pleaded not guilty to charges of presenting false Medicare claims to the federal government, September 8, 1972; 15.
      - Two members of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert W. Duggan's detective staff who face federal perjury charges were granted separate trials, September 11, 1972; 16.
      - Thornburgh announced that the special federal grand jury investigating trafficking in narcotics and dangerous drugs will commence this week, September 17, 1972; 17.
      - Voluntary compliance remains the key objective of the President's Economic Stabilization Program, September 18, 1972; 18.
      - The special federal grand jury returned its first indictments in the U.S. District Court in Pittsburgh, September 19, 1972; 19.
      - Thornburgh will be among nearly 100 top federal law enforcement officials present at a three-day conference in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina., September 21, 1972; 20.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Frederick Hoffmaster for the radio broadcast of "obscene, indecent and profane language" on four separate occasions, September 21, 1972; 21.
      - A federal grand jury indicted 10 persons for their part in a massive home repair and fraudulent home loan racket, September 21, 1972; 22.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a Johnstown doctor on thirty counts of illegal possession and storage of firearms and explosive materials in violation of federal laws, September 21, 1972; 23.
      - Blair A. Griffith will be the featured speaker at a dinner meeting in Monroeville of the Southwestern PA Chapter of the Associated Building Contractors, September 26, 1972; 24.
      - Three employees in the Thornburgh office have received special achievement awards from U.S. Attorney General Kleindienst for superior performance, September, 1972; 25.
      - A federal court jury convicted the most significant heroin distributor in the Pittsburgh area, September 29, 1972; 26.
    - October-December, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - The Department of Justice will seek an appeal to the U.S. Supreme Court in a landmark water pollution prosecution, October 4, 1972; 1.
      - Thornburgh filed criminal charges against two area companies on account of oil spills in violation of the Refuse Act of 1899, October 4, 1972; 2.
      - Dr. Ernest Eperjessy pleaded not guilty to thirty counts of illegal possession and storage of firearms and explosive materials, October 6, 1972; 3.
      - Judge Barron McCune sentenced Isadore Klein to serve jail time for tax evasion, October 6, 1972; 4.
      - An international heroin smuggling ring with its origins in the Middle East was smashed by a combined force of federal agents, October 6, 1972; 5.